

Luigene Villanueva

IT Support Engineer with expert analytical and communication skills. Expert at basic network troubleshooting routine network operations, including installation, setup, and backup of software, systems, printers, and hardware. Focused on customer satisfaction and building ongoing professional relations.

CONTACT

+971 562323820

9 +971 562323820

linkedin.com/in/luigene-villanueva

luigene.villanueva@gmail.com

Flat 1102, Al Mezaina Bldg, Al Nahda 1, Dubai, UAE

CERTIFICATION

Microsoft Certified:



Azure Fundamentals (AZ900)

Microsoft Fundamentals(MS900)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Board Exam Passer

December 2013 Electronics
Technician Licensure Examination

Graduated With Honors

Computer Engineering Technology

EDUCATION

BS Electronics and Communication Engineering

TUP Manila, 2011 - 2014 Manila, Philippines

BT Computer Engineering Technology

TUP Cavite, 2007 – 2011 Cavite, Philippines

EXPERIENCE

Company: Create Technology LLC (February 2023 - Present)

Designation: IT Engineer

- ❖ Maintenance & management of the Critical Windows based Server Environment.
- Working on Active Directory accounts, configuration of desktop & laptops.
- Managing and monitoring of backups in multiple locations.
- Troubleshooting technical problems and implementing solutions.
- Responsible for hardware and software installation, maintenance and repair.
- Managing the internal & hosted network infrastructure including Firewalls, Servers, Switches and Telephony.
- Managing and Email Creation for Office365.
- Developing & maintaining the company IT systems, software and databases.

Company: DXC Technology (March 2017 – September 2022)

Designation: Linux System Administrator

- ❖ Handle incidents and user raised request via ticketing tool (SM9, Service Now)
- Handle requests, outages, and escalation according to standard procedures and service level agreement
- Provide support for implementation, troubleshooting and maintenance of servers
- Linux filesystem management
- Update passwords of shared accounts that are soon to expire
- Monitor system performance and utilization
- Provide initial investigation / troubleshooting
- Extract, compile and send daily compliance report
- Conduct review to newly provisioned servers (physical / virtual) as per client standards / specifications
- Log vendor cases (HW / SW) and coordinate with the Engineer in investigating the issue
- Extract and upload necessary logs from Linux, SAN, 3PAR, ESX for analysis
- Creating change tasks for HW replacement and server decommissioning
- VMware decommissioning

Company: Accenture Inc. (April 2015 – February 2017)

Designation: Oracle / Peoplesoft Administrator

- Provided 2nd and 3rd level support, Installed computer peripherals for users.
- Server Administration (Windows / Linux), PeopleSoft Image Update, PeopleSoft PeopleTools Upgrade and Basic Oracle DB task
- Installation
 - PeopleSoft PeopleTools (Windows / Linux)
 - PeopleSoft Application [FSCM, HCM, CRM] (Windows / Linux)
 - Oracle Database [11g/12c] (Windows / Linux)
 - Oracle Tuxedo [11g/12c] (Windows / Linux)
 - Oracle WebLogic [11g/12c] (Windows / Linux)
 - JDK (Windows / Linux)